Sosuke Nishikawa

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

📞 090-4161-7403 | 🖂 sosuken115@gmail.com | 🏕 sosuke115.github.io | 🗘 Sosuke115 | in sosuke-nishikawa-2100581a0 | 💆 @ponyo_ponyo115

Personal Profile Statement

A master's student at the University of Tokyo with experience in software and machine learning. Skilled at operating in a wide range of platforms and programming. Praised for the ability to work hard and to achieve goals. Currently studying natural language processing using deep learning.

Education

- Master's student in Information Science and Technology, The University of Tokyo, Echizen lab. Apr. 2020 Present
- B.E. in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, The University of Tokyo, Tsuruoka lab. Mar. 2020, GPA: 3.8/4.0

Work and Research Experience _____

Echizen Lab, National Institute of Informatics

Tokyo, Japan

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Apr. 2020 - PRESENT

• Research fake news and biased news

Studio Ousia Tokyo, Japan

RESEARCH ENGINEER INTERN (PART TIME)

Feb. 2020 - PRESENT

• Research multilingual models

Stockmark Inc. Tokyo, Japan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN (PART TIME)

Dec. 2018 - Dec. 2019

• Created web application that allows users to understand at a glance who is familiar with which fields.

Publication

Analysis of bilingual word embeddings using pseudo corpus generated from Unsupervised Machine Translation

- NLP2020 (Japan)
- Sosuke Nishikawa, Yoshimasa Tsuruoka

Award

JGC-S scholarship foundation

Scholarship for study abroad program.

Competences _

Languages Japanese (native), English (conversant, IELTS 6.0)

Programming Python, JavaScript, Ruby, C, ŁTEX, HTML, CSS, mysql, Google Apps Script

Libraries Pytorch, Chainer, Tensorflow **Competitive prog.** Atcoder sosuke115 (rate 1003)